在上一讲中，我们讨论了机器人关节速度与关节之间的关系
In the last lecture, we talked about the relationship between the velocity of a robot's joints and
机器人末端执行器的速度，机器人末端执行器的姿势变化率。
the velocity of the robot end-effector, the rate of change of the pose of the robot end-effector.
而且，我们之前谈过这两个机器人问题，即前向运动学问题
And, we talked previously about these two robotic problems, the forward kinematic problem
和逆运动学问题，然后我们介绍了这个速度变换问题。
and the inverse kinematic problem and then we introduced this velocity transform problem.
在我们的上一次演讲中，我们在二维空间中做了一切。我们已经看过了
In our last lecture, we did everything in two-dimensional space. This we have seen a
通过本课程的次数。在两个方面，事情很容易。他们得到
number of times through this course. Things are pretty easy in two dimensions. They get
三维复杂得多。在本讲座中，我们将分三个部分进行
much more complex in three dimensions. In this lecture, we are going to do it in three
尺寸。所以现在，我们将定义它是什么
dimensions. So now, we are going to define what does it
意思是，这个psi点，就三维姿态随时间变化而言。所以，首先，我们是
mean, this psi dot, in terms of three-dimensional pose changing with time. So, first, we’re
将描述这个psi点是什么数学对象，然后我们将继续努力
going to describe what mathematical object this psi dot is and then we’re going to work on
关节角度与姿势率之间的关系。
the relationship between joint angle rates and pose rate.
现在，正如我们这样做，有一些先进的概念，如果你不是特别的话
Now, as we do this, there are some advanced concepts and, if you are not particularly
在数学方面很强，你没有差分微积分的背景，你不太舒服
strong at maths, you don’t have background in differential calculus, your not too comfortable
线性代数我们已经完成了一些线性代数。我们使用矩阵和
with linear algebra and we've done a bit of linear algebra already. We used matrices and
向量，但这可能是在更高级别使用的矩阵和向量。
vectors, but this is going to be perhaps matrix and vector used at a more advanced level.
如果你对这些概念不太满意，你可能会对这个特殊方面感到困惑
If you are not too comfortable with these concepts, you might struggle with this particular
演讲。所以，你的选择只是尝试和浏览讲座，观察
lecture. So, your options are just to try and skim through the lecture, observe the
即使你没有得到所有的细节，我想说的是要点。也许看
gist of what I’m trying to say even if you don’t get all of the details. Maybe look
在一些，一些额外的教科书。做一些阅读以获得，先决条件
at some, some additional textbooks. Do some more reading to get the, the prerequisites
你需要了解这一点。所以，只是一点点，之前的警告
that you are going need to understand that. So, just a little bit of a, of a warning before
我们深入了解它的细节。
we get in to the details of it.